{
  "problems": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "problem": "Social media websites use cheap AI softwares to moderate aggressive arguments, which often leads to deleting political opinions.",
      "solution": "The corporation decided to upgrade to a more expensive AI that prioritizes keeping political opinions over removing aggressive arguments.",
      "solution2": "The government mandated an upgrade to a more expensive AI that prioritizes keeping political opinions over removing aggressive arguments.",
      "benefitType": "money",
      "benefitText": "Around [number]% more opportunities to share politicial opinions for [affected]",
      "costType": "speech",
      "costText": "€[number] higher yearly platform fees"
    },
     {
      "id": 2,
      "problem": "Social media websites moderate calls for violence from extremist groups between users, which often leads to deleting political opinions.",
      "solution": "The corporation decided to upgrade to an AI that prioritizes keeping political opinions over removing calls for violence.",
      "solution2": "The government mandated an upgrade to an AI that prioritizes keeping political opinions over removing calls for violence.",
      "benefitType": "security",
      "benefitText": "Around [number]% more opportunities to share political opinions for [affected]",
      "costType": "speech",
      "costText": "[number]% higher public safety risks"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "problem": "Social media websites moderate aggressive arguments between users, which often lead to deleting political opinions.",
      "solution": "The corporation decided to upgrade to an AI that prioritizes keeping political opinions over removing aggressive arguments.",
      "solution2": "The government mandated an upgrade to an AI that prioritizes keeping political opinions over removing aggressive arguments.",
      "benefitType": "convenience",
      "benefitText": "Around [number]% more opportunities to share political opinions for [affected]",
      "costType": "speech",
      "costText": "[number]% worse experience for users"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "problem": "News outlets often try to publish the most engaging stories, which leads to some news being left out.",
      "solution": "The corporation decided to upgrade to an AI system that prioritizes informativeness in publishing.",
      "solution2": "The government mandated an upgrade to an AI system that prioritizes informativeness in publishing.",
      "benefitType": "convenience",
      "benefitText": "Around [number]% more access to investigative reporting from [affected] media outlets.", 
      "costType": "press",
      "costText": "[number]% worse news reading experience"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "problem": "News outlets often try to publish the most engaging stories, which leads to some news being left out.",
      "solution": "The corporation decided to upgrade to a more expensive AI system that prioritizes informativeness in publishing.",
      "solution2": "The government mandated an upgrade to a more expensive AI system that prioritizes informativeness in publishing.",
      "benefitType": "money",
      "benefitText": "Around [number]% more access to investigative reporting from [affected] media outlets.",
      "costType": "press",
      "costText": "€[number] higher yearly fees to access news" 
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "problem": "News outlets might downplay stories that could interfere with police operations, which leads to some news being left out.",
      "solution": "The corporation decided to upgrade to an AI system that prioritizes informativeness over police operations.",
      "solution2": "The government mandated an upgrade to an AI system that prioritizes informativeness over police operations.",
      "benefitType": "security",
      "benefitText": "Around [number]% more access to investigative reporting from [affected] media outlets",
      "costType": "press",
      "costText": "[number]% less likelihood of police catching criminals"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "problem": "Courts use an AI system that is biased in certain types of cases and leads to unfair sentencing.",
      "solution": "The corporation that owns the AI upgraded it to prioritze decreasing biases over speed.",
      "solution2": "The government mandated the upgrade of the AI system that prioritizes decreasing biases over speed.",
      "benefitType": "convenience",
      "benefitText": "Around [number]% more chance of fair sentencing in cases that usually affect [affected]",
      "costType": "due_process",
      "costText": "[number]% slower handling of court cases"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "problem": "Courts use an AI system that is biased in certain types of cases and leads to unfair sentencing.",
      "solution": "The corporation that owns the AI upgraded it to a more expensive model that prioritizes decreasing biases.",
      "solution2": "The government mandated the upgrade to a more expensive AI system that prioritizes decreasing biases.",
      "benefitType": "money",
      "benefitText": "Around [number]% more chance of fair sentencing in cases that usually affect [affected]",
      "costType": "due_process",
      "costText": "€[number] more taxes paid each year"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "problem": "Courts are using an AI system that is biased in certain types of cases and leads to sentencing innocent people to prison.",
      "solution": "The corporation that owns the AI upgraded it to prioritize keeping innocent people out of prioson.",
      "solution2": "The government mandated an upgrade to the AI system that prioritizes keeping innocent people out of prison.",
      "benefitType": "security",
      "benefitText": "Around [number]% more chance of fair sentencing in cases that usually affect [affected]",
      "costType": "due_process",
      "costText": "[number]% higher public safety risks"
    },
     {
      "id": 10,
      "problem": "Municipalities use an AI system that prioritizes traffic efficients when putting restrictions on protests.",
      "solution": "The corporation that owns the AI system upgraded it to prioritize accepting applications without restrictions except in extreme cases.",
      "solution2": "The government decides to change their AI system to prioritize accepting applications without restrictions except in extreme cases.",
      "benefitType": "convenience",
      "benefitText": "Around [number]% less chance of restrictions on protest location for [affected]",
      "costType": "assembly",
      "costText": "[number]% more traffic disruptions"
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "problem": "Municipalities use an AI system that prioritizes cost effectiveness when putting restrictions on protests.",
      "solution": "The corporation that owns the AI system upgraded it to prioritize accepting applications without restrictions except in extreme cases.",
      "solution2": "The government mandated an upgrade to the AI system to prioritize accepting applications without restrictions except in extreme cases.",
      "benefitType": "money",
      "benefitText": "Around [number]% less chances of restrictions on protest location for [affected]",
      "costType": "assembly",
      "costText": "€[number] more taxes paid each year"
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "problem": "Municipalities use an AI system that prioritizes public safety within the city when putting restrictions on protests.",
      "solution": "The corporation that owns the AI system upgraded it to prioritise accepting applications without any restriction except in the most extreme cases.",
      "solution2": "The government mandated an upgrade to the AI system to prioritise accepting applications without any restriction except in the most extreme cases.",
      "benefitType": "security",
      "benefitText": "Around [number]% less chances of restrictions on protest location for [affected]",
      "costType": "assembly",
      "costText": "[number]% higher public safety risks"
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "problem": "Municipalities use an AI system that takes private, sensitive information to decide on the truthfulness of benefit applications.",
      "solution": "The corporation that owns the AI system upgraded it to prioritize citizen privacy over finding out application truthfulness.",
      "solution2": "The government decides to change their AI system to prioritize citizen privacy over finding out application truthfulness.",
      "benefitType": "convenience",
      "benefitText": "Around [number]% less access to personal information for [affected]",
      "costType": "privacy",
      "costText": "[number]% less efficient municipality services"

    },
    {
      "id": 17,
      "problem": "Municipalities use an AI system that takes private, sensitive information to decide on the truthfulness of benefit applications.",
      "solution": "The corporation that owns the AI system upgraded it to prioritize citizen privacy over finding out application is truthfulness.",
      "solution2": "The government mandated an upgrade to the AI system to prioritize keeping citizen privacy over finding out application truthfulness.",
      "benefitType": "money",
      "benefitText": "Around [number]% less access to personal information for [affected]",
      "costType": "privacy",
      "costText": "€[number] more taxes paid each year to cover the additional benefits approved"
    },
    {
      "id": 18,
      "problem": "Police use an AI system that takes private, sensitive information to find violent criminals.",
      "solution": "The corporation that owns the AI system upgraded it to prioritize citizen privacy over locating violent criminals",
      "solution2": "The government mandated an upgrade to the AI system to prioritize citizen privacy over locating violent criminals",
      "benefitType": "security",
      "benefitText": "Around [number]% less access to personal information for [affected]",
      "costType": "privacy",
      "costText": "[number]% more public safety risks"
    },
        {
      "id": 19,
      "problem": "Some platforms allow personalized advertisement campaigns that manipulate and target people to sell products.",
      "solution": "The corporation that owns the AI system upgraded it to prioritize deleting personalized campaigns and advertisements.",
      "solution2": "The government mandated that platforms upgrade to AI recommender systems that prioritizes deleting personalized campaigns and advertisements.",
      "benefitType": "convenience",
      "benefitText": "Around [number]% less likely to be exposed to personalized campaigns targeting [affected]",
      "costType": "thought",
      "costText": "[number]% worse user experience."

    },
    {
      "id": 20,
      "problem": "Some platforms allow personalized advertisement campaigns that manipulate and target people to sell products.",
      "solution": "The corporation that owns the AI system upgraded it to prioritize deleting personalized campaigns and advertisements.",
      "solution2": "The government mandated that platforms upgrade to AI recommender systems that prioritizes deleting personalized campaigns and advertisements.",
      "benefitType": "money",
      "benefitText": "Around [number]% less likely to be exposed to personalized campaigns targeting [affected]",
      "costType": "thought",
      "costText": "€[number] higher yearly platform fees"
    },
    {
      "id": 21,
      "problem": "Some platforms allow radicalization reduction campaigns that target and manipulate people to change their minds.",
      "solution": "The corporation that owns the AI system upgraded it to prioritize deleting personalized campaigns and advertisements.",
      "solution2": "The government mandated that platforms upgrade to AI recommender systems that prioritizes deleting personalized campaigns and advertisements.",
      "benefitType": "security",
      "benefitText": "Around [number]% less likely to be exposed to personalized campaigns to reduce radicalization of [affected]",
      "costType": "thought",
      "costText": "[number]% higher public safety risks"
    }
  ]
}
